<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The Social Impact Guild - Top Positive Change News</title>
    <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com" />
    <updated>2021-11-08T11:24:18-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title> 🦉 Energy Wall and Owls</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/energy-wall-and-owls.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/energy-wall-and-owls.html</id>
            <category term="Newsletter"/>

        <updated>2021-11-08T11:24:18-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/owl-flying.jpg" alt="" />
                    <p><em>Hi</em> 👋 <strong>Did you know?</strong> If you enjoy watching horror movies, they might have a <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-58515-001">therapeutic effect</a> on you. Indeed, they allow some people to control their fears and manage stress in a safe environment.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/owl-flying.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><em>Hi</em> 👋 <strong>Did you know?</strong> If you enjoy watching horror movies, they might have a <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/record/2018-58515-001">therapeutic effect</a> on you. Indeed, they allow some people to control their fears and manage stress in a safe environment.</p>

<h2><strong>📈</strong><strong> Uplifting Trends and Facts</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Paris invested $260 million to become 100% bicycle-friendly by 2026. The "Plan Velo: Act 2" is part of a greater endeavour to remove cars from the city centre, including transforming the Champs-Élysées avenue into a vast community garden.</li>
<li>In Barcelona, drivers can exchange their old car for a 3-year <a href="https://www.tmb.cat/en/barcelona-fares-metro-bus/single-and-integrated/t-verda" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">free transit pass</a>. Since public transit infrastructure already exists, promoting such incentives is significantly cheaper for the city than advertising electric vehicles.</li>
<li>Thanks to environmental education and new legislation that criminalizes poaching and consuming turtles, the number of loggerhead sea turtle nests on Cap Verde beaches increased by 2000% <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/oct/26/fragile-success-cape-verde-sea-turtles-aoe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in the past six years</a>.</li>
<li>In a highly successful trial, a ship operated by <a href="https://socialimpactguild.com/the-company-that-wants-to-clean-up-the-ocean" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Ocean Cleanup</a> brought almost 30 tonnes of trash ashore. As a result, the non-profit organization now wants to scale up the operation to clean up the Great Pacific garbage patch.</li>
<li>Scientists studying carbon sequestration discovered that whales account for around <a href="https://farallones.org/climate/blue-carbon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">60 percent of annual sequestration</a> in the areas they live – more than seagrass, salt marshes and kelp put together. Preserving the whales could therefore be instrumental to fixing the climate.</li>
</ul>
<h2>💡 The Wall That Produces Energy From Wind</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/energywall-2.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/energywall-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/energywall-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/energywall-2-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="1920" height="1078"></figure>American designer and entrepreneur <a href="https://joedoucet.com/index#/windturbinewall/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joe Doucet</a> created a concept of a wind turbine that fits into a wall.</p>
<p>This "kinetic wall" comprises an array of rotary blades that spin individually, driving a mini generator that creates electricity. The electricity can then power the building to which the wall belongs or go back into the national grid, generating a new revenue stream for the owner.</p>
<p>However, this device is not only aesthetically pleasing. Indeed, one wall is enough to cover the energy needs of an average American home. Moreover, deploying such walls along roads and highways would be highly effective, as they would benefit from the natural wind and the wind generated by the trucks and cars passing by.</p>
<p>Joe is currently working with several manufacturers to help him develop and commercialize this exciting product.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> Wind energy plays a significant part in reducing the world's dependency on fossil fuels. However, wind turbines for homes have encountered very slow uptake due, in part, to their intrusive physicality. As a result, wind turbines flourish mainly offshore, where nobody can see them. This situation leads to wasting potential energy sources in cities prone to high winds, such as Wellington (New Zealand), Perth (Australia), Chicago or Boston (USA).</p>
<p>Joe's kinetic wall can be a gamechanger in these urban areas by covering all their energy needs.</p>
<h2><span style="font-family: 'Segoe UI Emoji',sans-serif;">🦉</span> The Owls That Replace Pesticides</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/owl-2.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/owl-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/owl-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/owl-2-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="1920" height="1080"></figure>Today, 80% of Napa Valley winemakers use owls to control their rodent population, while less than 20% use rodenticide instead.</p>
<p>Farmers realized that they only needed to build nest boxes near their fields to attract owls and reap the benefits. For example, a farmer with 20 owl boxes can expect those owls to catch around 70,000 rodents per year — which represents a cost of 26 cents per rodent, against several dollars for traditional methods (e.g. trapping, rodenticide).</p>
<p>Replacing pesticides with barn owls for rodent control is part of a broader environmentally sustainable trend among Napa Valley farmers. Indeed, many also reduce their water consumption in the face of Californian droughts and plant perennial grass between rows to prevent the danger of monoculture.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> For decades, Napa Valley's wineries relied on pesticides to prevent rodents from damaging their crops. However, this strategy, coupled with grapes-only monoculture and the usage of commercial fertilizer, generated a toxic taint in certain wines, demonstrating the need for more sustainable practices. In January 2021, California passed a law restricting rodenticides, but lobbying created a loophole for agricultural use.</p>
<p>Although still technically authorized, Napa's growers turned away from rodenticides because they understood that people and nature depend on each other to thrive. Also, they took this opportunity to make a few raptor friends along the way.</p>
<p>(source: <a href="https://baynature.org/article/raptors-rather-than-rodenticide" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">baynature.org</a>)</p>
<h2>🎯 The Guild's Pick</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/bananas-2.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/bananas-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/bananas-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/bananas-2-md.jpg 768w"  alt="" width="1920" height="1081"></figure>In France, <a href="https://www.lesartsverts-torreilles.fr/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Les Arts Verts</a> grow tropical produce in greenhouses to reduce the carbon footprint associated with importing food from around the globe.</p>
<p>These pioneer farmers in the Pyrenees produce bananas, turmeric, passionfruit, mangos, and many other species that we usually find in La Réunion (a French department in the Indian Ocean). Their secret is to find species that can handle conditions colder than the tropics to flourish in European greenhouses.</p>
<p>Moreover, Les Arts Verts grow their food according to the organic certification ECOCERT. In particular, they cultivate their tropical produce in living spaces, using polyculture to keep the soil rich and increase biodiversity. Also, they do not heat their greenhouses but equip them with solar panels to put clean electricity back into the grid.</p>
<p>Finally, this farm collaborates with the greatest French chefs—including a Michelin-starred restaurant— to provide them with zero-carbon exotic products.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> Bananas and mangos are among the preferred fruits in France. The country imports <a href="https://www.fruitlogistica.com/FRUIT-LOGISTICA/Downloads-Alle-Sprachen/Auf-einen-Blick/European_Statistics_Handbook_2019.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3.4 million metric tons of fruit</a> every year, despite the vast amount of farms within its borders. However, importing 2 tons of products can generate 6 tons of carbon dioxide and its greenhouse gas equivalent.</p>
<p>Eco-conscious consumers in France will now be able to get their favourite tropical fruits while enabling the creation of local jobs and preventing adverse effects on the environment.</p>
<h2>🌍 Meanwhile, Worldwide …</h2>
<p>💧 Alphabet's X lab recently open-sourced the data, prototypes, software, and hardware documentation of its atmospheric water harvester, a device producing safe drinking water from air humidity. This move aims to improve the device's efficiency to give more than 1 billion people access to clean drinking water.</p>
<p>🐮 A team of scientists in Dummerstorf, Germany and Auckland, New Zealand, discovered that <a href="https://www.cell.com/current-biology/fulltext/S0960-9822(21)00966-0#%20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">potty-training cows</a> could lead to a 56 percent reduction in ammonia emissions, which cause acid rain, NOx pollution and contamination in rivers.</p>
<p>🌱 The Swedish non-profit Milkywire created a curated list of carbon offsetting projects to help corporations support climate action as part of their CSR. The organization designed its "<a href="https://www.milkywire.com/climate-transformation-portfolio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">climate transformation portfolio</a>" to contain only credible and impactful projects.</p>
<p>🥗 Compass Group <a href="https://www.compass-group.co.uk/media/news/compass-group-uk-ireland-to-roll-out-eco-labels-across-business-industry-estate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">rolled out an eco-label</a>, displaying products' ecological impact, across its workplace catering sites. This initiative occurred after a successful pilot project with researchers from Oxford's <a href="https://www.leap.ox.ac.uk/home#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Livestock, Environment and People</a> (LEAP) that triggered a statistically significant shift towards ecologically greener foods among the participants, including a 10 percent reduction in meat consumption.</p>
<p>🌽 Researchers from the Chinese Academy of Sciences found a way to produce starch more sustainably. The new method creates this versatile cooking ingredient <a href="https://phys.org/news/2021-09-chinese-scientists-starch-synthesis-carbon.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">from carbon dioxide</a>, using 90% fewer resources than the traditional approach (e.g. corn) and only 11 biochemical reactions instead of 60.</p>
<h2><span role="image" aria-label="😍">😍</span> Wholesomeness</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="file:///C:/Users/nphum/Documents/Publii/sites/the-social-impact-guild-top-positive-change-news/input/media/posts/temp/wholesomeness21.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="file:///C:/Users/nphum/Documents/Publii/sites/the-social-impact-guild-top-positive-change-news/input/media/posts/temp/responsive/wholesomeness21-xs.png 300w ,file:///C:/Users/nphum/Documents/Publii/sites/the-social-impact-guild-top-positive-change-news/input/media/posts/temp/responsive/wholesomeness21-sm.png 480w ,file:///C:/Users/nphum/Documents/Publii/sites/the-social-impact-guild-top-positive-change-news/input/media/posts/temp/responsive/wholesomeness21-md.png 768w"  alt="" width="2589" height="2586"></figure><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/wholesomeness21-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/wholesomeness21-2-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/wholesomeness21-2-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/117/responsive/wholesomeness21-2-md.png 768w"  alt="" width="2589" height="2586"></figure>
<hr>
<p>That’s a wrap. If you enjoyed this newsletter, please share this post to spread positivity among your friends. For any feedback, reach out and drop a comment here or on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/social-impact-guild/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a> :-)</p>
<p>Have an amazing week ahead 💗</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>New hydrogel tablets can purify contaminated water in minutes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/new-hydrogel-tablets-can-purify-contaminated-water-in-minutes.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/new-hydrogel-tablets-can-purify-contaminated-water-in-minutes.html</id>
            <category term="Water"/>
            <category term="Communities"/>

        <updated>2021-10-26T15:33:56-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/116/water.jpeg" alt="" />
                    Scientists and engineers at The University of Texas at Austin have created a hydrogel tablet to purify contaminated water rapidly.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/116/water.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>Scientists and engineers at The University of Texas at Austin have created a hydrogel tablet to <a href="https://news.utexas.edu/2021/10/05/this-hydrogel-tablet-can-purify-a-liter-of-river-water-in-an-hour/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">purify contaminated water</a> rapidly.</p>
<p>One tablet can clean a litre of water and make it drinkable in less than an hour. The hydrogel generates hydrogen peroxide to neutralize more than 99.999% of bacteria by attacking their essential cell components and disrupting their metabolism.</p>
<p>Moreover, the researchers say that scaling production would be straightforward. Indeed, materials are cheap, and the synthesis process is simple, even at scale. Also, they can control the tablets’ shape and size to adapt them to different use cases.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> Almost a third of the world does not have clean drinking water, and half of the population could experience extreme water scarcity by 2025. The existing purification processes rely on boiling water, which requires a lot of energy and time, and is not practical for the people who lack clean water the most.</p>
<p>Finding a solution to the water crisis could save millions of people. In this context, these hydrogel tablets can make a massive difference as they are easy to use, highly efficient and scalable to mass production.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A pub lets you pay your beer with old iPhones</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/a-pub-lets-you-pay-your-beer-with-old-iphones.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/a-pub-lets-you-pay-your-beer-with-old-iphones.html</id>
            <category term="Circular Economy"/>

        <updated>2021-10-26T15:33:21-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/115/beers.jpg" alt="" />
                    In London, the Trade-Inn pub lets you pay for your food and beverages with electronic waste. This pub accepts almost&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/115/beers.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>In London, the <a href="https://spring.co.uk/trade-inn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trade-Inn pub</a> lets you pay for your food and beverages with electronic waste.</p>
<p>This pub accepts almost 14,000 electronic devices—including old iPhones—that they repair and resell afterwards or recycle if too damaged.</p>
<p>​<a href="https://spring.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spring</a>, the company behind this project, is a new tech recirculation service that opens pods throughout England where people can drop their old tech in exchange for actual money.</p>
<p>So far, Spring has resold or recycled around 13,000 devices, saving almost 1,000 tonnes of CO2 emissions and diverting more than 2 tonnes of e-waste from landfills. Moreover, the company is currently working on opening a shop that sells refurbished items only.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> Each year, the UK produces 1.6 million tonnes of electronic waste and is forecast to be Europe’s biggest producer by 2024. Today, much of this waste ends up in a landfill or incinerated, affecting the environment considerably.</p>
<p><strong>What can we do?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>An average adult owns around 20 unused electronic devices. Putting them back in circulation would reduce the demand for new devices and the related environmental impact. Also, sorting and reselling our old tech can be highly beneficial for our bank account.</li>
<li>Although our old laptop might no longer be enough for us, many schools, libraries, or charities might give it a new purpose. The best way to donate a computer is to reach out to a third-party organization, such as <a href="https://spring.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digitunity</a> or the <a href="https://spring.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">World Computer Exchange</a>.</li>
<li>Finally, cloud storage (Google Drive, Dropbox, etc.) lets us reduce our reliance on hard drives and USB sticks to store our data, limiting the amount of e-waste we generate.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond the genius marketing stunt, the Trade-Inn pub raises awareness about electronic waste and provides an easy way to give our old devices a new life.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>DroneSeed leverages drone technology to further reforestation efforts</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/droneseed-leverages-drone-technology-to-further-reforestation-efforts.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/droneseed-leverages-drone-technology-to-further-reforestation-efforts.html</id>
            <category term="Global Warming"/>
            <category term="Biodiversity"/>

        <updated>2021-10-26T15:31:19-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/114/trees.jpeg" alt="" />
                    DroneSeed developed a drone-based technology to reforest lands after wildfires efficiently. The drones pack everything new trees need to thrive:&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/114/trees.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p><a href="https://droneseed.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DroneSeed</a> developed a drone-based technology to reforest lands after wildfires efficiently.</p>
<p>The drones pack everything new trees need to thrive: seeds, nutrients, and natural pest deterrent. Also, the company uses laser mapping technology to determine where the seeds have the highest chance of survival to optimize the process.</p>
<p>DroneSeed can reforest up to 50 acres per day with five drones and four employees. In contrast, traditional reforestation methods that plant nursery-grown trees by hand can only cover 2 acres per day and cost up to 50% more.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> The severity and frequency of recent wildfires threaten Nature’s capacity to reforest. Without intervention, most of these forests could disappear in the following decades, with dramatic repercussions on biodiversity, air quality and global warming.</p>
<p><strong>What can we do?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The easiest way to prevent fire from spreading is never to leave a campfire or fire pit unattended. Also, we should make sure to extinguish it completely before leaving.</li>
<li>Under certain conditions, even a small campfire can turn into a significant fire. Therefore, it’s preferable to alert the authorities immediately whenever we spot an unattended fire — even a small one.</li>
</ul>
<p>DroneSeed has aggregated decades' worth of experience to develop tools that give us a fighting chance against climate change's effects on our forests.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What&#x27;s up this week? Coldplay will harness their fans&#x27; energy to make their concerts more sustainable and more.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/whats-up-this-week-coldplay-will-harness-their-fans-energy-to-make-their-concerts-more-sustainable-and-more.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/whats-up-this-week-coldplay-will-harness-their-fans-energy-to-make-their-concerts-more-sustainable-and-more.html</id>
            <category term="Uplifting Trends &amp; Facts"/>

        <updated>2021-10-26T15:29:44-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/113/coldplay.jpg" alt="" />
                    For their next World Tour, music band Coldplay will harness their fans' energy to make their concerts more sustainable. Indeed,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/113/coldplay.jpg" alt="" />
                <ul>
<li>For their next World Tour, music band Coldplay will harness their fans' energy to make their concerts <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20211014-coldplay-announce-eco-friendly-tour-with-kinetic-flooring" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more sustainable</a>. Indeed, the band will capture the energy of dancing fans through kinetic flooring.</li>
<li>New Zealand <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/new-zealand-passes-climate-change-disclosure-laws-financial-firms-world-first-2021-10-21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">passed a law</a> that makes banks, insurers, and investment companies disclose the impacts of climate change on their business. The goal is for them to "become more sustainable by factoring the short, medium, and long-term effects of climate change into their business decisions." New Zealand is the first country to pass such legislation.</li>
<li>New evidence shows Vikings arrived in North America precisely 1000 years ago, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03972-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 1021</a>. Although we already knew that the Norse reached America way before Columbus, it's the first time we pinpoint their exact arrival date in Newfoundland.</li>
<li>In the UK, investments in impact ventures (early-stage startups with a social mission) climbed <a href="https://bigsocietycapital.com/our-approach/market-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by 41% in 2020</a>. These impact ventures have been particularly resilient to the crisis, especially those working in the tech sector.</li>
<li>South Korea officially committed to reducing carbon emissions by 40% <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/skorea-commits-challenging-goal-cutting-emissions-40-2018-levels-by-2030-2021-10-18/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by the end of the decade</a>. This necessary target is quite ambitious as the country is currently one of the world’s most fossil-fuel reliant economies, with coal accounting for more than 44% of the country’s electricity.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>🍻 Drones and Beers</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/drones-and-beers.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/drones-and-beers.html</id>
            <category term="Newsletter"/>

        <updated>2021-11-08T11:22:31-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/112/drones-reforestation.jpg" alt="" />
                    Hui 👋 Did you know? A new study suggests that dogs can distinguish between humans' intentional and unintentional actions, reflecting&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/112/drones-reforestation.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span data-key="929"><em data-slate-mark="true"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">Hui </span></em><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">👋 </span><strong data-slate-mark="true"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">Did you know? </span></strong><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">A new </span><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true"><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-94374-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">study</a> suggests that dogs can distinguish between humans' intentional and unintentional actions, reflecting that the bond between dogs and humans is even deeper than we previously thought.</span></span></p>
<h2>📈 <a href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/whats-up-this-week-coldplay-will-harness-their-fans-energy-to-make-their-concerts-more-sustainable-and-more.html">Uplifting Trends and Facts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>For their next World Tour, music band Coldplay will harness their fans' energy to make their concerts <a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20211014-coldplay-announce-eco-friendly-tour-with-kinetic-flooring" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">more sustainable</a>. Indeed, the band will capture the energy of dancing fans through kinetic flooring.</li>
<li>New Zealand <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/sustainable-business/new-zealand-passes-climate-change-disclosure-laws-financial-firms-world-first-2021-10-21/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">passed a law</a> that makes banks, insurers, and investment companies disclose the impacts of climate change on their business. The goal is for them to "become more sustainable by factoring the short, medium, and long-term effects of climate change into their business decisions." New Zealand is the first country to pass such legislation.</li>
<li>New evidence shows Vikings arrived in North America precisely 1000 years ago, <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03972-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in 1021</a>. Although we already knew that the Norse reached America way before Columbus, it's the first time we pinpoint their exact arrival date in Newfoundland.</li>
<li>In the UK, investments in impact ventures (early-stage startups with a social mission) climbed <a href="https://bigsocietycapital.com/our-approach/market-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by 41% in 2020</a>. These impact ventures have been particularly resilient to the crisis, especially those working in the tech sector.</li>
<li>South Korea officially committed to reducing carbon emissions by 40% <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/skorea-commits-challenging-goal-cutting-emissions-40-2018-levels-by-2030-2021-10-18/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">by the end of the decade</a>. This necessary target is quite ambitious as the country is currently one of the world’s most fossil-fuel reliant economies, with coal accounting for more than 44% of the country’s electricity.</li>
</ul>
<h2>🌳 <a href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/droneseed-leverages-drone-technology-to-further-reforestation-efforts.html">The Drones That Plant Trees</a></h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"><img loading="lazy"  tabindex="0" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/VCzTaKsI8BgsJWQkLnoHQ5Q7SO4DeliycuMUUo-TbkmiXVg8xyEIx7eIll669Pjr-XEqFYsBILjc-xxnMuRMRdcar5YLXpKrBfIOdUf0eB1wb9sRql5is6A32XwHMYY=s0-d-e1-ft#https://embed.filekitcdn.com/e/6LWZH6HHXUYuf2ryKDVC5T/kRTvmhTc5iJS9WA5XypMRV" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="" width="800"></figure></span></p>
<p><a href="https://droneseed.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">DroneSeed</a> developed a drone-based technology to reforest lands after wildfires efficiently.</p>
<p>The drones pack everything new trees need to thrive: seeds, nutrients, and natural pest deterrent. Also, the company uses laser mapping technology to determine where the seeds have the highest chance of survival to optimize the process.</p>
<p>DroneSeed can reforest up to 50 acres per day with five drones and four employees. In contrast, traditional reforestation methods that plant nursery-grown trees by hand can only cover 2 acres per day and cost up to 50% more.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> The severity and frequency of recent wildfires threaten Nature’s capacity to reforest. Without intervention, most of these forests could disappear in the following decades, with dramatic repercussions on biodiversity, air quality and global warming.</p>
<p><strong>What can we do?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The easiest way to prevent fire from spreading is never to leave a campfire or fire pit unattended. Also, we should make sure to extinguish it completely before leaving.</li>
<li>Under certain conditions, even a small campfire can turn into a significant fire. Therefore, it’s preferable to alert the authorities immediately whenever we spot an unattended fire — even a small one.</li>
</ul>
<p>DroneSeed has aggregated decades' worth of experience to develop tools that give us a fighting chance against climate change's effects on our forests.</p>
<h2>🍻 <a href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/a-pub-lets-you-pay-your-beer-with-old-iphones.html">The Pub That Trades Beers For E-waste</a></h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"><img loading="lazy"  tabindex="0" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/_lmJwPQ3CrSLoMG1uMIFfdklxUV5C3Iq5dH2D5Zu6veHZB0AUlUnfGOi5bVexSwu-TVHJJZhGIu22lVjR9tszH9JBiPTmBPShvpxK8tdxKsxMb29NrvtFWPx7JMRWnQ=s0-d-e1-ft#https://embed.filekitcdn.com/e/6LWZH6HHXUYuf2ryKDVC5T/wDu3bdmwoaW2cJRJg296pN" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="" width="800"></figure></span></p>
<p>In London, the <a href="https://spring.co.uk/trade-inn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Trade-Inn pub</a> lets you pay for your food and beverages with electronic waste.</p>
<p>This pub accepts almost 14,000 electronic devices—including old iPhones—that they repair and resell afterwards or recycle if too damaged.</p>
<p>​<a href="https://spring.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spring</a>, the company behind this project, is a new tech recirculation service that opens pods throughout England where people can drop their old tech in exchange for actual money.</p>
<p>So far, Spring has resold or recycled around 13,000 devices, saving almost 1,000 tonnes of CO2 emissions and diverting more than 2 tonnes of e-waste from landfills. Moreover, the company is currently working on opening a shop that sells refurbished items only.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> Each year, the UK produces 1.6 million tonnes of electronic waste and is forecast to be Europe’s biggest producer by 2024. Today, much of this waste ends up in a landfill or incinerated, affecting the environment considerably.</p>
<p><strong>What can we do?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>An average adult owns around 20 unused electronic devices. Putting them back in circulation would reduce the demand for new devices and the related environmental impact. Also, sorting and reselling our old tech can be highly beneficial for our bank account.</li>
<li>Although our old laptop might no longer be enough for us, many schools, libraries, or charities might give it a new purpose. The best way to donate a computer is to reach out to a third-party organization, such as <a href="https://digitunity.org/get-involved/give-equipment/donate-your-computer/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digitunity</a> or the <a href="https://worldcomputerexchange.org/get-involved/give-computers/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">World Computer Exchange</a>.</li>
<li>Finally, cloud storage (Google Drive, Dropbox, etc.) lets us reduce our reliance on hard drives and USB sticks to store our data, limiting the amount of e-waste we generate.</li>
</ul>
<p>Beyond the genius marketing stunt, the Trade-Inn pub raises awareness about electronic waste and provides an easy way to give our old devices a new life.</p>
<h2>🎯 <a href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/new-hydrogel-tablets-can-purify-contaminated-water-in-minutes.html">Guild’s Pick</a></h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  tabindex="0" src="https://ci3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/r6aIfbV43wbSv0CeVrvlSRU3Q6cmXbkrjGzQZ7foV-nkKDEzsHhSidOYGYIz17l4xZDTVszoxM8RUH-zOYv3YPFCcvsA-tI_z5AlSHP4uqTBAwGivVPrT_xAjlBcHls=s0-d-e1-ft#https://embed.filekitcdn.com/e/6LWZH6HHXUYuf2ryKDVC5T/8dWKo5SLZq9pJroiv6qVbq" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="" width="800"></figure>
<p>Scientists and engineers at The University of Texas at Austin have created a hydrogel tablet to <a href="https://news.utexas.edu/2021/10/05/this-hydrogel-tablet-can-purify-a-liter-of-river-water-in-an-hour/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">purify contaminated water</a> rapidly.</p>
<p>One tablet can clean a litre of water and make it drinkable in less than an hour. The hydrogel generates hydrogen peroxide to neutralize more than 99.999% of bacteria by attacking their essential cell components and disrupting their metabolism.</p>
<p>Moreover, the researchers say that scaling production would be straightforward. Indeed, materials are cheap, and the synthesis process is simple, even at scale. Also, they can control the tablets’ shape and size to adapt them to different use cases.</p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong> Almost a third of the world does not have clean drinking water, and half of the population could experience extreme water scarcity by 2025. The existing purification processes rely on boiling water, which requires a lot of energy and time, and is not practical for the people who lack clean water the most.</p>
<p>Finding a solution to the water crisis could save millions of people. In this context, these hydrogel tablets can make a massive difference as they are easy to use, highly efficient and scalable to mass production.</p>
<h2>🌎 Meanwhile, Worldwide...</h2>
<p data-key="1074"><span data-key="1075"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">🚘 Swedish automobile manufacturer Volvo wants all of its vehicles to be leather-free by 2030. In a recent <a href="https://www.media.volvocars.com/uk/en-gb/media/pressreleases/286448/volvo-cars-to-go-leather-free-in-all-pure-electric-cars-as-part-of-animal-welfare-ambitions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">press release</a>, the company announced a series of sustainability-related initiatives to become a fully circular business by 2040.</span></span></p>
<p data-key="1079"><span data-key="1080"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">🦊 The California Department of Transportation will build a wildlife crossing in the Agoura Hills, <a href="https://savelacougars.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SaveLACougars-Overview-2019-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over Highway 101</a>. Today, this busy eight-lane highway prevents many animals from travelling freely between the two mountainous areas, limiting genetic diversity and leading some species to extinction.</span></span></p>
<p data-key="1084"><span data-key="1085"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">👕 Ralph Lauren <a href="https://corporate.ralphlauren.com/pr_210322_ColorOnDemand.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">brought together</a> innovators to develop a way to colour cotton using 90% fewer chemicals, 50% less water, 50% less dye and 40% less energy than traditional methods. This month, the companies released an <a href="https://www.dow.com/en-us/brand/ecofast.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">open-source manual</a> detailing how to achieve the same result with already existing dyeing equipment.</span></span></p>
<p data-key="1092"><span data-key="1093"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">🧊 The WWF and British Antarctic Survey seek help from the public to monitor the number of walrus in the Arctic using satellite images. The <a href="https://www.wwf.org.uk/learn/walrus-from-space" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Walrus From Space</a><em> </em>project aims to paint a clear picture of the walrus population without disturbing the animals.</span></span></p>
<p data-key="1097"><span data-key="1098"><span spellcheck="true" data-slate-content="true">🐚 Researchers from McGill University developed <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abf0277" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a new type of glass</a>, inspired by the inner layer of mollusc shells, five times more resistant than traditional glass. They hope manufacturers will use this new material to replace cell phone glass and other electronics components. </span></span></p>
<h2>😊 Wholesomeness</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/112/cat_meme.jpeg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/112/responsive/cat_meme-xs.jpeg 300w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/112/responsive/cat_meme-sm.jpeg 480w ,https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/112/responsive/cat_meme-md.jpeg 768w"  alt="" width="431" height="535"></figure>
<hr>
<p>That’s a wrap. If you enjoyed this newsletter, please share this post to spread positivity among your friends. For any feedback, reach out and drop a comment here or on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/social-impact-guild/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a> :-)</p>
<p>Have an amazing week ahead 💗</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Japan wants to harness the energy of super typhoons to reach climate goals</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/japan-wants-to-harness-the-energy-of-super-typhoons-to-reach-climate-goals.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/japan-wants-to-harness-the-energy-of-super-typhoons-to-reach-climate-goals.html</id>
            <category term="Energy"/>

        <updated>2021-10-18T11:34:47-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/110/typhoon.jpg" alt="" />
                    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Japanese "Typoonshot" project aims to mitigate typhoon-related risks and harness their energy to help the country reach zero carbon emissions by 2050.</span></p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/110/typhoon.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Japanese "Typoonshot" project aims to mitigate typhoon-related risks and harness their energy to help the country reach zero carbon emissions by 2050.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the brand new Typhoon Science and Technology Research Center at </span><a href="https://www.ynu.ac.jp/english/" target="null"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yokohama National University</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, researchers, analysts and experts are working together to find ways to reduce the damage typhoons cause and collect the massive amount of clean energy they generate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the project is only at the beginning, experts already consider many methods to achieve its goals. The first experiment they hope to conduct soon involves injecting large amounts of ice into the storm's eye to reduce its overall pressure and intensity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another idea is to deploy a fleet of remote-controlled ships into a storm that gathers and stores energy from wind and undersea turbines. In fact, according to their estimation, the energy of a single powerful typhoon could meet the global demand for energy for an entire month!</span></p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter?</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Today, mainland Japan is relatively safe from super typhoons. However, the country already suffers from "regular" typhoons, and climate change is likely to send more powerful ones in the years to come. Also, Japan's access to energy sources is limited, and many worry about the country's zero carbon emissions target by 2050.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Harnessing a super typhoon's energy seems like a highly challenging task. However, success in such a game-changing endeavour would completely change how we see typhoons. Indeed, they would become a blessing rather than a threat.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(source: </span><a href="https://www.dw.com/en/japan-bids-to-harness-the-energy-of-super-typhoons/a-59483087" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">dw.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">)</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Furniture made from eelgrass, good for the environment and your health</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/furniture-made-from-eelgrass-good-for-the-environment-and-your-health.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/furniture-made-from-eelgrass-good-for-the-environment-and-your-health.html</id>
            <category term="Circular Economy"/>
            <category term="Air Quality"/>

        <updated>2021-10-29T10:09:40-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/109/eelgrass.jpg" alt="" />
                    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Danish startup </span><a href="https://www.sould.dk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Søuld</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> produces eco-friendly building materials from eelgrass.</span></p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/109/eelgrass.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Danish startup </span><a href="https://www.sould.dk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Søuld</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> produces eco-friendly building materials from eelgrass.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The use of eelgrass as a building material dates back 400 years ago when Danish folks were using this highly available sea plant as a roofing material. After ten years of research and development, Søuld adapted that traditional building technique into a modern process that leverages the eelgrass’ CO2-binding properties to create furniture that also serves as a carbon sink.</span></p>
<p>Also, this highly fashionable, recyclable and non-toxic furniture creates a healthier indoor environment. Indeed, it dampens noise, provides acoustic comfort, and absorbs and releases moisture without rotting, resulting in a healthy indoor climate free from noise, bacteria, mould, and other microbes.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, these products also offer thermal insulation and resistance to fire and can last more than 150 years, contributing to a smaller overall environmental footprint.</span></p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter? </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US </span><a href="https://www.epa.gov/outdoor-air-quality-data"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Environmental Protection Agency</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> indicated that indoor air pollutants are often 2 to 5 times higher than outdoor levels, leading to asthma, decreased lung function and heart issues. And, with the average American spending 87% of their life indoors, indoor air quality is even more crucial.</span></p>
<p><strong>What else can we do?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depending on our location, the weather can generate humid conditions, breeding mould in our home. In this context, investing in a dehumidifier can go a long way to creating a healthier environment.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our homes usually feature many filters that help us eliminate pollutants, dust and allergens. However, we should make sure to change the filter of our vacuum cleaner, clothes dryer, kitchen vent and AC regularly to ensure their proper functioning – especially if we live in a metropolitan area with high pollution levels.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, we can leverage nature and install a few indoor plants to clean our environment while improving our mood and enhancing our home décor. Small plants like ferns and lilies and larger palm trees are the best options to pull contaminants out of the air. However, be careful about potential allergies before your next trip to your local florist!</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Søuld’s approach respects the cultural heritage of eelgrass while meeting the design and environmental needs of today.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What&#x27;s up this week? Some buildings in Paris have witnessed a 47% drop in their energy bill and more.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/whats-up-this-week-some-buildings-in-paris-have-witnessed-a-47-drop-in-their-energy-bill-and-more.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/whats-up-this-week-some-buildings-in-paris-have-witnessed-a-47-drop-in-their-energy-bill-and-more.html</id>
            <category term="Uplifting Trends &amp; Facts"/>

        <updated>2021-10-19T08:01:37-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/108/paris.jpg" alt="" />
                    Paris pledged to reduce its public housings’ energy consumption by 60% by 2030. After a decade of efforts, including changing&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/108/paris.jpg" alt="" />
                <ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paris pledged to reduce its public housings’ energy consumption by 60% by 2030. After a decade of efforts, including changing the insulation and renovating the heating systems and electrical wiring, some of the largest buildings already witnessed </span><a href="https://grist.org/housing/paris-shows-how-to-make-public-housing-greener-and-more-habitable-at-the-same-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a 47% drop</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in their energy bill.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The UN declared access to a clean environment </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/environment/un-passes-resolution-making-clean-environment-access-human-right-2021-10-08/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a human right</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This resolution is not legally binding yet but has the potential to shape global standards and can help lawyers build arguments in cases involving the environment and human rights. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google will ban YouTube videos and other content </span><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-58831379" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">denying climate change</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and prohibit ads promoting these claims. This move echoes a </span><a href="https://secure.avaaz.org/campaign/en/youtube_climate_misinformation/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2020 report</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> accusing YouTube of "incentivizing climate misinformation via its monetization program."</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a joint report by the Academy of Medical Sciences and the Royal Society, improving insulation in homes would help </span><a href="https://acmedsci.ac.uk/file-download/11365167" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">prevent 50,000 premature deaths</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the UK alone every year.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) presented proof that <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/explainers/sustaining-our-nation-s-fisheries" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">sustainable fishing policies work</a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Indeed, these policies have helped rebuild 43 fish stocks since 2000. As a result, 84% of reserves are no longer overfished today.</span></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Aether creates the world&#x27;s first carbon-negative diamonds</title>
        <author>
            <name>Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/aether-creates-the-worlds-first-carbon-negative-diamonds.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/aether-creates-the-worlds-first-carbon-negative-diamonds.html</id>
            <category term="Global Warming"/>

        <updated>2021-10-18T11:59:24-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/107/diamonds.jpg" alt="" />
                    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After years of research, </span><a href="https://aetherdiamonds.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aether Diamonds</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cracked the technology allowing them to create the world’s first carbon-negative diamonds.</span></p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.socialimpactguild.com/media/posts/107/diamonds.jpg" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After years of research, </span><a href="https://aetherdiamonds.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aether Diamonds</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> cracked the technology allowing them to create the world’s first carbon-negative diamonds.</span></p>

<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In essence, a diamond is a piece of carbon crushed to a point where its atoms form a specific structure. Traditionally, jewellers let Nature do this part and extract diamonds directly from the Earth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, Aether flipped the script and developed a process to create diamonds from air pollution, effectively removing carbon from the air for each carat they produce. Moreover, the company achieved an overall carbon-negative footprint by using only renewable and low-emission sources throughout the process.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, a two-carat ring will offset roughly 40 metric tonnes of carbon emissions, corresponding to two and a half years of a typical American person’s emissions.</span></p>
<p><strong>Why does it matter? </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">As highlighted by movies like “Blood Diamond,” traditional diamond production enables human exploitation, conflicts and environmental devastation. In terms of global warming alone, the diamond trade is responsible for at least 12 million metric tonnes of carbon dioxide emissions each year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks to its game-changing technology, Aether offers a conflict-free and eco-friendly alternative that features the same physical, chemical and optical characteristics as ‘traditional’ diamonds.</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
